<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="104" moduleid="5893" modulename="book" contextid="19772">
  <book id="104">
    <name>Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA)</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;IDEA section&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1468873882</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1469044222</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="804">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Under IDEA, the school system must identify and diagnose disabilities</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Under IDEA, the school system must identify and diagnose disabilities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s first talk about The Individuals With Disabilities Education Act (IDEA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IDEA serves the needs of students with disabilities, starting with early identification, which can occur at birth through exit from high school, and must occur by age 21. Some states extend this age beyond 21. To be covered by this law, students must be part of a school system (or expected to be part of a school system for those birth to 4 years old).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Children who are suspected of having a disability are referred to school personnel for identification and diagnosis. It is the responsibility of the school system to provide diagnostic services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/GC1_playground.jpg" width="580" height="431" alt="Photo of children on a playground." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468943423</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="805">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>IEP specifies an appropriate intervention plan for students</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;IEP specifies an appropriate intervention plan for students&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p class="Subhead"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal; line-height: 1.231;"&gt;If one or more disabilities are identified, then an intervention plan called an &lt;/span&gt;&lt;b style="font-size: 13px; line-height: 1.231;"&gt;individualized education program (IEP)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal; line-height: 1.231;"&gt; is developed. An IEP identifies the special education and any needed related services (such as speech therapy or counseling) that will be delivered. These services must be delivered at no cost to the family. Thus, individuals identified with one or more disabilities under IDEA are entitled to services.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entitlement is supported by funding to schools for special education and related services.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1469738800</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="806">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>SOPs facilitate a successful transition to postsecondary environments</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;SOPs facilitate a successful transition to postsecondary environments&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of interest to programs supporting adults with LD, IDEA also provides a process for students to prepare for transition from high school. IDEA mandates that transition planning be part of the IEP starting at age 16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One relatively new part of the transition planning process is the development of a &lt;b&gt;Summary of Performance (SOP)&lt;/b&gt; document. The purpose of the SOP is to facilitate the student’s successful movement from secondary school to postsecondary environments by developing a school exiting document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SOP is a summary or synthesis of the student’s goals and future plans, accomplishments (both academic and functional skills), and needs (including accommodations). For individuals with LD, this document should provide diagnostic information and list accommodations important in postsecondary education and employment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/GC1_ClassroomGirl.jpg" width="580" height="435" alt="Stock photo of a high school classroom of students. " /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468964337</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="807">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Identify ways a SOP could facilitate entry into your program</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Identify ways a SOP could facilitate entry into your program&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the SOP is a relatively new mandate, it is implemented in a variety of ways. Ideally, the student should play an active part in developing the SOP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A goal is for postsecondary programs to accept the SOP as disability documentation and a guide to effective accommodations. However, most postsecondary institutions do not accept the SOP unless a recent diagnostic report (within two to three years) is attached.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to consider the following question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style="margin-left: 30px;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: medium;"&gt;How do you think a Summary of Performance document could facilitate an individual’s entry into your program?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/GC1_counselor.jpg" width="580" height="435" alt="Photo of a guidance counselor conferring with a student." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have generated some ideas, click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; to proceed. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468965035</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="808">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>SOP provides information to help meet the needs of adults with LD</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;SOP provides information to help meet the needs of adults with LD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many programs, the Summary of Performance (SOP) would provide some description of the nature of the disability (or disabilities) as well as a clear description of an individual’s strengths and needs in educational, career, and community settings. This information is often invaluable in planning instruction and services to meet the needs of adults with specific learning disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next let’s talk about the Rehabilitation Act.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468965107</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>