<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="105" moduleid="5894" modulename="book" contextid="19773">
  <book id="105">
    <name>Rehabilitation Act</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;Rehab Act Studies section&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1468873882</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1468965084</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="809">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Rehab act designed to prevent discrimination against people with disabilities</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Rehab act designed to prevent discrimination against people with disabilities&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As noted previously, the Rehabilitation Act is also known as the Rehab Act. This law was enacted to prevent discrimination against individuals with disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passed in 1973, this law uses the terms “handicapped” and “non-handicapped.”  These terms are no longer used in the disability community. Instead, the term “individuals with disabilities” is currently used. The language in the Rehab Act, however, does not reflect this change, and we will occasionally use these out-dated terms when citing this law. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal; line-height: 1.231;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal; line-height: 1.231;"&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/GC1_WomanWheelchairWorking.jpg" width="580" height="445" alt="Photo of a woman in a wheelchair, working at a computer." /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468967946</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="810">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Rehab Act applies to all individuals</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Rehab Act applies to all individuals&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rehab Act applies to all organizations receiving federal funding  including government entities, non-profit organizations, and federal contractors, as well as both &lt;b&gt;K-12 and post-secondary &lt;/b&gt;education organizations. Unlike &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;IDEA&lt;/span&gt;, the Rehab act applies to individuals of any age.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468967979</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="811">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Rehab Act provides for equal access, regardless of disability</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Rehab Act provides for equal access, regardless of disability&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One purpose of the Rehab Act is to offer individuals with disabilities the same opportunities to succeed as nondisabled individuals. This is called &lt;b&gt;equal access&lt;/b&gt;. Equal access means that qualified persons with disabilities should have an equal opportunity to participate in or benefit from their education or employment situations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key to equal access is that the individual be &lt;b&gt;qualified&lt;/b&gt;. For example, if there are entrance requirements for an educational program, the individual with a disability must meet those requirements. This also applies to employment. If there are basic education or experience requirements, the individual must meet them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equal access means that a qualified person may not be discriminated against &lt;i&gt;because &lt;/i&gt;of a disability.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468968013</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="812">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Rehab Act calls for reasonable accommodations</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Rehab Act calls for reasonable accommodations&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way the Rehab Act promotes nondiscrimination is through reasonable accommodations. Accommodations are modifications or adjustments to the person and/or environment that enable a person with a disability to more fully access or participate in education, employment or the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the Rehab Act states that accommodation services  “are not required to produce the identical result or level of achievement for handicapped and non-handicapped persons, but must afford handicapped persons equal opportunity to obtain the same result, to gain the same benefit, or to reach the same level of achievement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal is not to give individuals with disabilities advantages, but to allow them the chance to fully participate with reasonable accommodations. This idea is sometimes called “leveling the playing field.” Let’s look at two examples of reasonable accommodations.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468968067</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="813">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Identify reasonable accommodations in a school environment</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Identify reasonable accommodations in a school environment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a school example: For Sarah, who struggles with reading, someone reads a science test aloud. The reader reads exactly what is on the page and does not provide additional information unless that &lt;i&gt;same&lt;/i&gt; additional information is provided to &lt;i&gt;all&lt;/i&gt; the test takers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to consider, why would this be considered a reasonable accommodation under the Rehab Act?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/GC1_TeenGirls.jpg" width="350" height="462" alt="Photo of two teenage girls looking at a document." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After you have finished your reflections, click the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; to continue.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468968378</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="814">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Identify reasonable accommodations in a school environment (cont.)</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Identify reasonable accommodations in a school environment (cont.)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since Sarah’s reader reads exactly what is on the page and does not provide additional information unless that same additional information is provided to all the test takers, Sarah’s accommodations do not give her an undue advantage over the other students, nor do her accommodations make an unreasonable demand on school resources.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468968227</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="815">
        <pagenum>7</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Identify reasonable accommodations in a work environment</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Identify reasonable accommodations in a work environment&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a work example: Alexi, an employee in a manufacturing environment, has difficulty remembering task sequences. In written instructions provided by the supervisor, each major task is broken down into sequential steps. Each subpart is color coded for easy reference (green means start, red means stop, etc.).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, take a moment to consider, why would this be considered a reasonable accommodation under the Rehab Act?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="line-height: 1.231;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/GC1_MachineGuy.jpg" width="350" height="451" alt="Photo of a young man in a factory sorting small parts." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;After you have finished your reflections, click the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt; to continue.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468968355</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="816">
        <pagenum>8</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Identify reasonable accommodations in a work environment (cont.)</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Identify reasonable accommodations in a work environment (cont.)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alexi’s accommodations (color-coded written instructions) do not give him undue advantage over his peers, nor do his accommodations make an unreasonable demand on the resources of his employer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that Alexi’s example is drawn from the &lt;a href="http://askjan.org/soar/LD/LDex.html" target="_blank"&gt;Job Accommodation Network&lt;/a&gt;, an online resource of the U.S. Department of Labor’s Office of Disability Employment Policy. More examples are provided in the Resources section at the end of this course.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468968423</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="817">
        <pagenum>9</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Rehab Act requires self-disclosure and self-advocacy</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Rehab Act requires &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt; and self-advocacy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some limitations of the Rehab Act relevant to individuals with LD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rehab Act does not require an educational program or employer to reach out to or identify a qualified individual with a disability. Once admitted to an educational program or employed, the individual has the responsibility to self-disclose a disability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, it can take more than &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt; to access accommodations and services. A person may need to self-advocate, meaning provide a clear description of his or her areas of strength as well as needs and ways he or she has learned to compensate for the specific areas of disability. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1469738846</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="818">
        <pagenum>10</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Rehab Act does not provide for diagnostic services</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Rehab Act does not provide for diagnostic services&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rehab Act does not provide or mention any guidelines for evaluation or assessment. Individuals must provide their own documentation of disability. Postsecondary institutions are under no obligation to pay for evaluations or assessments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State vocational agencies receive some federal funds that must be matched by state funds for services to individuals with disabilities. Services can include funding for diagnostic assessments, attendance at postsecondary education such as college, employment-related training and access to supports (e.g., assistive technology and transportation) for employment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rehabilitation agencies often face more demand for services than available funding supports. Individuals receive support based on the severity of their needs. This process is called &lt;b&gt;order of selection&lt;/b&gt;. Individuals with LD are often not considered in severe enough need to be funded for diagnostic and other services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #993300;"&gt;Continue on to the Quiz: Identify the provisions of the Rehab Act and IDEA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1469648411</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>