<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="107" moduleid="5900" modulename="book" contextid="19779">
  <book id="107">
    <name>Comparing IDEA, Rehab Act, and ADAAA</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;compare section&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1468873882</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1468972434</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="822">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Comparing IDEA, Rehab Act, and ADAAA</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Comparing IDEA, Rehab Act, and ADAAA&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This diagram summarizes important aspects of IDEA, the Rehab Act, and the ADAAA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at this diagram, we can see that all three of these laws share a common purpose: to protect the rights of people with disabilities by prohibiting discrimination on the basis of disability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Venn_Diagram.jpg" width="538" height="438" alt="A Venn diagram with three overlapping ovals; one green (labeled “IDEA”), one orange (labeled “Rehab Act”), and one purple (labeled “ADAAA”). The green top oval gives the main points of IDEA: “Serves birth-21 only; Entitlement to services; K-12 and Pre-K only; Provides for identification and diagnosis; and SOP document.” Where the green IDEA oval and the orange Rehab Act oval intersect, it is labeled “Services.”  The intersection of all three ovals is labeled, “Purpose: non-discrimination.” The orange Rehab Act oval lists these main points: “Limited funding via ‘order of selection’” and “Protection limited to services/employment with federally funded entities.”  The area where the orange oval and the purple oval intersect lists these points in common: “Serves any age,” “Requires self-disclosure,” and “’Reasonable accommodations.’”  The purple ADAA oval lists these points as being unique to ADAAA: “Protects access to broad range of society, including most adult life situations” and “No services.” " /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468971380</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="823">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Distinctive elements of IDEA</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Distinctive elements of IDEA&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can see that IDEA is distinctive because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;it is limited to students who are participating in special education services in a K-12 setting;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once identified, a student is entitled to special education and related services;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once students exit school, the act no longer applies to their education;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once a student is referred, the school system is responsible for the identification and diagnostic process; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;students who graduate or exit as part of the IEP process should have an SOP document, which can be useful for adult service providers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/VD_IDEAhighlighted.jpg" width="560" height="455" alt="A Venn diagram with three overlapping ovals; one green (labeled “IDEA”), one orange (labeled “Rehab Act”), and one purple (labeled “ADAAA”). The green top oval gives the main points of IDEA: “Serves birth-21 only; Entitlement to services; K-12 and Pre-K only; Provides for identification and diagnosis; and SOP document.” This oval is highlighted. Where the green IDEA oval and the orange Rehab Act oval intersect, it is labeled “Services.”  The intersection of all three ovals is labeled, “Purpose: non-discrimination.” The orange Rehab Act oval lists these main points: “Limited funding via ‘order of selection’” and “Protection limited to services/employment with federally funded entities.”  The area where the orange oval and the purple oval intersect lists these points in common: “Serves any age,” “Requires self-disclosure,” and “’Reasonable accommodations.’”  The purple ADAA oval lists these points as being unique to ADAAA: “Protects access to broad range of society, including most adult life situations” and “No services.” " /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468971441</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="824">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Distinctive elements of the Rehab Act</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Distinctive elements of the Rehab Act&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Rehab Act is distinctive due to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the provision of limited funding for services, with no guarantee of services as they are provided on a competitive system, based on need; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;non-discrimination is limited to employment and services provided by entities under federal contract or receiving federal funding – including educational institutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/VD_Rehab_highlighted.jpg" width="560" height="455" alt="A Venn diagram with three overlapping ovals; one green (labeled “IDEA”), one orange (labeled “Rehab Act”), and one purple (labeled “ADAAA”). The green top oval gives the main points of IDEA: “Serves birth-21 only; Entitlement to services; K-12 and Pre-K only; Provides for identification and diagnosis; and SOP document.”  Where the green IDEA oval and the orange Rehab Act oval intersect, it is labeled “Services.”  The intersection of all three ovals is labeled, “Purpose: non-discrimination.” The orange Rehab Act oval lists these main points: “Limited funding via ‘order of selection’” and “Protection limited to services/employment with federally funded entities.” This oval is highlighted. The area where the orange oval and the purple oval intersect lists these points in common: “Serves any age,” “Requires self-disclosure,” and “’Reasonable accommodations.’”  The purple ADAA oval lists these points as being unique to ADAAA: “Protects access to broad range of society, including most adult life situations” and “No services.” " /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468971570</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="825">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Distinctive elements of the ADAAA</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Distinctive elements of the ADAAA&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ADAAA is distinctive because it extends non-discrimination protections to a broad range of American society, not limited by federal funding or K-12 school settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition, note that it provides no funding for services relative to its provisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/VD_ADAAAhighlighted.jpg" width="550" height="447" alt="A Venn diagram with three overlapping ovals; one green (labeled “IDEA”), one orange (labeled “Rehab Act”), and one purple (labeled “ADAAA”). The green top oval gives the main points of IDEA: “Serves birth-21 only; Entitlement to services; K-12 and Pre-K only; Provides for identification and diagnosis; and SOP document.”  Where the green IDEA oval and the orange Rehab Act oval intersect, it is labeled “Services.”  The intersection of all three ovals is labeled, “Purpose: non-discrimination.” The orange Rehab Act oval lists these main points: “Limited funding via ‘order of selection’” and “Protection limited to services/employment with federally funded entities.”  The area where the orange oval and the purple oval intersect lists these points in common: “Serves any age,” “Requires self-disclosure,” and “’Reasonable accommodations.’”  The purple ADAA oval lists these points as being unique to ADAAA: “Protects access to broad range of society, including most adult life situations” and “No services.” This oval is highlighted." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468971621</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="826">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>IDEA and Rehab Act both provide funds for services</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;IDEA and Rehab Act both provide funds for services&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that both the IDEA and the Rehab Act provide funds for services, but as we have noted, under IDEA, once an individual is diagnosed, services are provided, whereas under the Rehab Act, individuals with LD may find services difficult to access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/VD_SERVICEShighlighted.jpg" width="560" height="455" alt="A Venn diagram with three overlapping ovals; one green (labeled “IDEA”), one orange (labeled “Rehab Act”), and one purple (labeled “ADAAA”). The green top oval gives the main points of IDEA: “Serves birth-21 only; Entitlement to services; K-12 and Pre-K only; Provides for identification and diagnosis; and SOP document.”  Where the green IDEA oval and the orange Rehab Act oval intersect, it is labeled “Services.” This area is highlighted. The intersection of all three ovals is labeled, “Purpose: non-discrimination.” The orange Rehab Act oval lists these main points: “Limited funding via ‘order of selection’” and “Protection limited to services/employment with federally funded entities.”  The area where the orange oval and the purple oval intersect lists these points in common: “Serves any age,” “Requires self-disclosure,” and “’Reasonable accommodations.’”  The purple ADAA oval lists these points as being unique to ADAAA: “Protects access to broad range of society, including most adult life situations” and “No services.”" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468971715</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="827">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Provisions provided by both ADAAA and Rehab Act</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Provisions provided by both ADAAA and Rehab Act&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the ADAAA and the Rehab Act both&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;apply to individuals of any age;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;require an individual to disclose his or her disability in order to gain benefits from the laws; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;employers and agencies to provide  “reasonable accommodations.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the next activity, we will ask you to reflect on what you have learned about the Rehab Act and the ADAAA and consider the implications of these two laws for the adult learners you serve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/VD_NonDisc_highlight.jpg" width="560" height="455" alt="A Venn diagram with three overlapping ovals; one green (labeled “IDEA”), one orange (labeled “Rehab Act”), and one purple (labeled “ADAAA”). The green top oval gives the main points of IDEA: “Serves birth-21 only; Entitlement to services; K-12 and Pre-K only; Provides for identification and diagnosis; and SOP document.”  Where the green IDEA oval and the orange Rehab Act oval intersect, it is labeled “Services.”  The intersection of all three ovals is labeled, “Purpose: non-discrimination.” The orange Rehab Act oval lists these main points: “Limited funding via ‘order of selection’” and “Protection limited to services/employment with federally funded entities.”  The area where the orange oval and the purple oval intersect is highlighted. It lists these points in common: “Serves any age,” “Requires self-disclosure,” and “’Reasonable accommodations.’”  The purple ADAA oval lists these points as being unique to ADAAA: “Protects access to broad range of society, including most adult life situations” and “No services.”" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468971780</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="828">
        <pagenum>7</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Identify the benefits of the Rehab Act and ADAAA to adults with LD</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Identify the benefits of the Rehab Act and ADAAA to adults with LD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given what you have learned so far in this course, what &lt;b&gt;benefits&lt;/b&gt; do you think the Rehab Act and ADAAA provide to the adults you serve who may have a learning disability?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please write down your thoughts for review later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/VD_RehabADAAAonly.jpg" width="560" height="278" alt="A Venn diagram with two overlapping ovals; one orange (labeled “Rehab Act”), and one purple (labeled “ADAAA”).  The orange Rehab Act oval lists these main points: “Limited funding via ‘order of selection’” and “Protection limited to services/employment with federally funded entities.”  Where the orange oval and the purple oval intersect, it lists these points in common: “Serves any age,” “Requires self-disclosure,” and “’Reasonable accommodations.’”  The purple ADAA oval lists these points as being unique to ADAAA: “Protects access to broad range of society, including most adult life situations” and “No services.” " /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you have completed your reflections, click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow &lt;/b&gt;to proceed.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468971844</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="829">
        <pagenum>8</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Benefits of the Rehab Act and ADAAA to adults with LD</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Benefits of the Rehab Act and ADAAA to adults with LD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While other answers may apply, the most significant benefits of the Rehab Act and the ADAAA to individuals with disabilities are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individuals with disabilities cannot be denied access to educational services because of their disabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Individuals with disabilities have a right to reasonable accommodations on the job, in education, and in almost all adult life situations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to compare your reflections with those listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; to consider the limitations of these two laws.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468971873</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="830">
        <pagenum>9</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Identify the limitations of the Rehab Act and ADAAA for adults with LD</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Identify the limitations of the Rehab Act and ADAAA for adults with LD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given what you have learned so far in this course, what &lt;b&gt;limitations&lt;/b&gt; do you think these two laws present to the adults you serve who may have a learning disability?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please write down your thoughts for review later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/VD_RehabADAAAonly.jpg" width="560" height="278" alt="A Venn diagram with two overlapping ovals; one orange (labeled “Rehab Act”), and one purple (labeled “ADAAA”).  The orange Rehab Act oval lists these main points: “Limited funding via ‘order of selection’” and “Protection limited to services/employment with federally funded entities.”  Where the orange oval and the purple oval intersect, it lists these points in common: “Serves any age,” “Requires self-disclosure,” and “’Reasonable accommodations.’”  The purple ADAA oval lists these points as being unique to ADAAA: “Protects access to broad range of society, including most adult life situations” and “No services.” " /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #000000;"&gt;When you have completed your reflections, click the &lt;strong&gt;forward arrow&lt;/strong&gt; to proceed.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1469132941</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="831">
        <pagenum>10</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Limitations of the Rehab Act and ADAAA for adults with LD</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Limitations of the Rehab Act and ADAAA for adults with LD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While other answers may apply, the most significant limitations of the Rehab Act and the ADAAA to individuals with LD wishing to access accommodation are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;He or she will have to advocate for accommodations by disclosing the disability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The individual will also have to provide their own documentation of the disability. This means the individual must have a good understanding of his or her disability and be comfortable identifying what he or she needs to be successful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access to funding for diagnosis or services is limited and individuals with learning disabilities are likely to have difficulties accessing funded services due to the ‘order of selection’ process. This may make it difficult to self-advocate for accommodations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to compare your answers with those listed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While addressing our first guiding question: “Which federal laws affect adults with LD?” we noted that both the Rehab Act and ADAAA require &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt; in order to access reasonable accommodations. This leads us to our next guiding question.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1469132858</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="832">
        <pagenum>11</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Printout of the Venn diagram is available in the Resources section</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Printout of the Venn diagram is available in the Resources section&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This Venn Diagram provides a good overview of the three Laws affecting adults with disabilities. The &lt;b&gt;Resources&lt;/b&gt; section at the end of this course includes a printer-friendly version of the diagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While addressing our first guiding question: “Which federal laws affect adults with LD?” we noted that both the Rehab Act and ADAAA require &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt; in order to access reasonable accommodations. This leads us to our next guiding question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/Venn_Diagram.jpg" width="560" height="455" alt="A Venn diagram with three overlapping ovals; one green (labeled “IDEA”), one orange (labeled “Rehab Act”), and one purple (labeled “ADAAA”). The green top oval gives the main points of IDEA: “Serves birth-21 only; Entitlement to services; K-12 and Pre-K only; Provides for identification and diagnosis; and SOP document.” Where the green IDEA oval and the orange Rehab Act oval intersect, it is labeled “Services.”  The intersection of all three ovals is labeled, “Purpose: non-discrimination.” The orange Rehab Act oval lists these main points: “Limited funding via ‘order of selection’” and “Protection limited to services/employment with federally funded entities.”  The area where the orange oval and the purple oval intersect lists these points in common: “Serves any age,” “Requires self-disclosure,” and “’Reasonable accommodations.’”  The purple ADAA oval lists these points as being unique to ADAAA: “Protects access to broad range of society, including most adult life situations” and “No services.” " /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #993300;"&gt;Continue on to Guiding Question #2, Disclosure - Self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1469132993</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>