<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="108" moduleid="5901" modulename="book" contextid="19780">
  <book id="108">
    <name>Self-disclosure</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;Self-disclosure section&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1468873882</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1468972675</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="833">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Choosing to disclose or not disclose</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Choosing to disclose or not disclose&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our second guiding question asks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What does choosing &lt;b&gt;to disclose or not to disclose &lt;/b&gt;mean to adults with LD?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s first consider what is involved in the self-disclosure process – what does self-disclosure mean? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/GC2_WomanMask.jpg" width="300" height="450" alt="Photo of a woman holding a mask near her face, as if she has just revealed herself." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size: 13px; font-weight: normal; line-height: 1.231;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468972791</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="834">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Disclosure decision and accommodations for adults with LD</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Disclosure decision and accommodations for adults with LD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a disability context, “disclosure” means that people with disabilities share information about their disability for the specific purpose of receiving accommodations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned previously, accommodations are supports that an individual needs to function in learning or employment environments as a way to compensate for a diagnosed disability. As we have just discussed, accommodations are legal rights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adults with non-apparent or hidden disabilities, such as a learning disability, need to decide what, if anything, they want to disclose. This can be a difficult decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These adults should decide to whom they want to disclose and how much information to provide. Generally, adults with LD find it most beneficial to disclose information only if they need accommodations.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468972814</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="835">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Documentation for self disclosure</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Documentation for self disclosure&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adults with LD should provide documentation as a part of self disclosure. Documentation can be a letter or a report from an evaluation professional. The evaluation should state how the learning disability affects the individual’s performance and should recommend reasonable accommodations. Remember, neither employers nor postsecondary education programs are required to perform this evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The individual should be able to specifically describe strengths, such as, “I am good at understanding oral directions” and needs, such as, “I have difficulty reading master schedules and I need help finding the information that is specific to me.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If requested, the individual should be prepared to share further information, such as the methods used in the diagnostic process of the evaluation, including names of specific tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve briefly examined the process for individuals with LD to self-disclose in order to receive accommodations; however, choosing to self-disclose is not an easy decision. Let’s next examine the pros and cons of self-disclosure for an adult with LD. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468972836</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="836">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Identify reasons for choosing not to self disclose LD</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Identify reasons for choosing not to self disclose LD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please take a moment to reflect on your experiences with adults with learning disabilities, as well as what you have learned so far in this course. What are some of the reasons a person would choose NOT to self-disclose a learning disability?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/GC2_WomanSign.jpg" width="414" height="432" alt="Photo of a woman holding a sign that says “Self-Disclosure.”" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have thought about your answer, click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; to compare your reasons to ours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468972923</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="837">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Reasons some choose not to self disclose LD</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Reasons some choose not to self disclose LD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-disclosure is a difficult process. Reasons individuals sometimes choose not to self-disclosure include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;fear of being treated differently;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they view their LD as a sign of weakness;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;lack of documentation of their LD;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cost of obtaining a private evaluation is too high;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they do not know how to effectively describe their LD; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;concern that self-disclosure will lead to negative reactions of peers or supervisors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your reflections may have found even more reasons individuals may choose not to disclose. It is important to respond to those who are wary of self-disclosure with a list of BOTH pros and cons, so they can make an informed decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, let’s consider some of the advantages of self-disclosing LD.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468972948</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="838">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Identify advantages of self-disclosure for adults with LD</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Identify advantages of self-disclosure for adults with LD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, take a moment to reflect on your experiences with adults with learning disabilities, as well as what you have learned so far in this Course. What are some of the advantages to self-disclosure for adults with documented LD?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After you have thought about your answer, click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; to proceed. &lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468972976</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="839">
        <pagenum>7</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Advantages of self-disclosure for adults with LD</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Advantages of self-disclosure for adults with LD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many advantages to self-disclosure for adults with documented LD. Compare your list of advantages to those listed here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-disclosure allows individuals to receive reasonable accommodations to pursue school and work activities more effectively.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-disclosure can lead to development of a support network of trained professionals (educators, employment service providers, etc.) to help individuals adjust to challenges they face in education and workplace environments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-disclosure provides legal protection against discrimination (as specified in the Rehab Act and the ADAAA).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, self-disclosure can improve an individual’s self-image by helping him or her develop and improve self-advocacy skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your reflections may have found even more reasons individuals may choose to self-disclose. It is very important, however, to appreciate the courage it can take to self-disclose and take time to think about supportive ways of responding if an individual chooses to do so. But deciding to self-disclose is just the first step of the process.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468972998</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="840">
        <pagenum>8</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Self-disclosure and self-determination</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Self-disclosure and self-determination&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Self-disclosure links to the self-determination process in terms of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the importance of knowing oneself;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;valuing oneself;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;planning;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;being proactive; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;reflecting and readjusting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A supportive environment is also important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information on self-determination for adult learners with specific learning disabilities in adult education contexts can be found in the &lt;a href="https://courses.lincs.ed.gov/1/" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Self-Determination course&lt;/a&gt; of the Learning to Achieve online learning series. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="color: #993300;"&gt;Continue on to the Decision-making process&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1468973121</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>