<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<activity id="110" moduleid="5903" modulename="book" contextid="19782">
  <book id="110">
    <name>Supporting Self-disclosure</name>
    <intro>&lt;p&gt;Supporting Self-Disclosure&lt;/p&gt;</intro>
    <introformat>1</introformat>
    <numbering>0</numbering>
    <customtitles>1</customtitles>
    <timecreated>1469570476</timecreated>
    <timemodified>1469817994</timemodified>
    <chapters>
      <chapter id="854">
        <pagenum>1</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Supporting adults with LD in the self-disclosure process</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Supporting adults with LD in the &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt; process&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ve talked about this multifaceted approach and how complicated it is, so how do individuals learn methods for &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, individuals with LD need help to develop self-understanding and to find compensatory strategies and accommodations that work. This fact highlights the importance of educators helping students develop self-determination. Let’s take a look at what you can do to support adult students with LD in the s&lt;span class="nolink"&gt;elf-disclosure&lt;/span&gt; process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/SelfDisclosureGraphic_COMPLETE.png" width="560" height="561" alt="Diagram consisting of four circles surrounding a fifth circle. The center circle is labeled, “Self-Disclosure.” Arrows point outward from the center circle to each of the four surrounding circles. The four circles are labeled, “Where? When? What? and How?”" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1469570573</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="855">
        <pagenum>2</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Reflect on your program’s intake process</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Reflect on your program’s intake process&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To wrap up our discussion on &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt;, let’s take some time to examine supports for &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt; in adult education settings – specifically in your own program or organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a moment to reflect on the intake process in your organization. Consider the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What forms and procedures does your program use during the intake process that might allow an individual to disclose a learning disability? &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does your organization currently support individuals with suspected LD to develop the important skill of &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click the &lt;b&gt;forward arrow&lt;/b&gt; when you have completed your reflections.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1469642346</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="856">
        <pagenum>3</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Supporting the development of self-disclosure skills</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Supporting the development of &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt; skills&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few examples of support programs you may have in place, or can implement,  to support the development of &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt; skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For teachers, support for &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt; can be as simple as inviting individuals who have LD (or other disabilities) to self-disclose. This can be a simple oral invitation when a class begins. In open enrollment courses, this can be done when groups of new individuals enter the class or program.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With informed consent, mentors and or tutors can support individuals with LD by providing instruction and practice in s&lt;span class="nolink"&gt;elf-disclosure&lt;/span&gt; skills.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1469642383</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="857">
        <pagenum>4</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Support for individuals without documentation of their LD</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Support for individuals without documentation of their LD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, an individual with suspected learning disabilities may not have and/or may not be able to obtain documentation. Again, with informed consent, you can still try to help these individuals build &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt; skills as well as improve their success in your program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teachers, counselors, mentors, and/or tutors can:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;invite students to tell what in the past has indicated that he or she has a learning disability;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;encourage them to explore and discuss their strengths and weaknesses as learners and employees; or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ask them to share what strategies have (and have not) assisted them in completing learning and/or work related tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1469642420</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="858">
        <pagenum>5</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Confidentiality at intake</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;&lt;span class="nolink"&gt;Confidentiality&lt;/span&gt; at intake&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When considering your organization’s intake and support processes in regard to &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt;, it is important to note that it is not appropriate to single out certain individuals and directly ask if they have disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Options to open the door for disclosure by individuals you suspect may have a disability include questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Describe your high school program. Did you receive extra help in school?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Do you have specific concerns about entering this program?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;“Describe your areas of strength and areas you would like to improve.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that many programs have intake forms with questions people may answer &lt;i&gt;voluntarily&lt;/i&gt;  (regarding ethnicity, food stamps, housing vouchers, disability, etc.). Such voluntary check boxes are not the same as “asking directly“ and are administered to all individuals, thus no person or group is “singled out.”  Forms and processes like this are unlikely to violate &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;confidentiality&lt;/span&gt; requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will take a closer look at issues of &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;confidentiality&lt;/span&gt; next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="@@PLUGINFILE@@/GC2_counselorRedShirt.jpg" width="570" height="428" alt="Photo of an adult student and an intake counselor." /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1469739440</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
      <chapter id="859">
        <pagenum>6</pagenum>
        <subchapter>0</subchapter>
        <title>Activity: Share your ideas for improving your program’s self-disclosure support for individuals with LD</title>
        <content>&lt;h1 class="Subhead"&gt;Activity: Share your ideas for improving your program’s &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt; support for individuals with LD&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on what you have learned so far in this course, consider the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How might you improve or add to your intake process to better support &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt; by individuals with LD?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How might you or your organization improve or add to what they currently do to support individuals with suspected LD to develop the skill of &lt;span class="nolink"&gt;self-disclosure&lt;/span&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please share your thoughts and read other teachers’ responses in the &lt;a href="https://community.lincs.ed.gov/discussion/online-course-learning-achieve-legal-issues-self-disclosure-and-confidentiality-adults" target="_blank"&gt;LINCS Disabilities in Adult Education Group&lt;/a&gt; before moving on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="Prompt"&gt;&lt;span style="color: #993300;"&gt;When you have finished posting your reflections, continue on to Guiding Question #3, Confidentiality&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content>
        <contentformat>1</contentformat>
        <hidden>0</hidden>
        <timemodified>1469645010</timemodified>
        <importsrc></importsrc>
      </chapter>
    </chapters>
  </book>
</activity>